Armando Ivan Gonzalez

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

2012904979 armando.gonzalez97@gmail.com

Links

<u>Personal Website</u> <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Georgia Tech Mascot Feature</u>

Skills

Languages

Scala Java VueJS SQL

Frameworks and Tools

AWS Kafka

Akka Git

Ionic Kubernetes

Practices

Backend Software Development

Functional Programming

Object Oriented Programming

Agile Software Development

Communication

Technical Writing

Public Speaking

Project Management

Involvements

Georgia Tech Mascot (Buzz) Georgia Tech Orientation Georgia Tech Teacher's Assistant

Education

B.S. in Computer Science Georgia Institute of Technology Class of 2020

Summary

Armando Gonzalez is a passionate, personable team player with multiple years of experience in software engineering and an eagerness for developing large-scale products. In his free time, he enjoys free writing and making art of many forms.

Employment History

Associate Software Engineer | The Walt Disney Company

May 2020 - May 2021 | New York, NY

- Served on the team that managed the Video On Demand (VOD) Orchestration and Media Processing Pipeline for Disney+, ESPN+, and eventually Star+ and Hulu
- Developed, maintained, and vended systems that processed and distributed high fidelity media content to 100+ million subscribers worldwide
- Acted as technical lead for the development and design of several features related to the automatic validation of incoming media assets
- Contributed to many projects that were on the critical path to the company's success in the streaming market
- Saved the department development hours and improved the robustness of its systems through contributions to our build and deployment pipelines
- Assisted in organizing and running virtual events aimed at recruitment and Diversity & Inclusion, such as interviews, college visits, and networking events

Software Engineering Intern | The Walt Disney Company

June 2019 - August 2019 | New York, NY

- Partnered on a media distribution workflow that supported the future global streaming expansion efforts of the Walt Disney Company
- Independently contributed alongside full time developers preparing for the launch of Disney+
- Designed the cloud infrastructure for an experimental Disney+ search page Hackathon project that won Most Creative Use of AWS
- Delivered several formal demos to other members of the Services organization

Software Engineering Coop | Patientco

Fall 2017 - May 2019 (rotating with undergraduate semesters) | Atlanta, GA

- Led a small team that developed a net-new service utilizing computer vision to automatically read
 patient information from mailed checks to support our human operators
- Discovered a major security and compliance vulnerability in one of our vendors' sites
- Formally recruited for the company by attending career fairs and delivering a Tech Talk on my final project on Georgia Tech's campus

Software Engineering Intern | BAMTech Media, LLC

May 2020 - May 2021 | New York, NY

- Worked as an independent, full-stack contributor for the first time
- Developed production level software supporting a global multimedia processing pipeline

Software Engineering Intern | MLB, Advanced Media

May 2020 - May 2021 | New York, NY

- Shortly graduated from small project tickets for full-stack service development
- Implemented a proof-of-concept project backing the search engine of a web portal which helped our internal operators search and catalog a partner's media assets
- Delivered formal demos and presentations to other interns and members of the department

Personal Projects

- Conexus (WIP) a mobile application aimed at connecting individuals interested in joint real estate investments
- Vitreus (WIP) a personal magic mirror running as a web app intended for RaspberryPi